# **Brandon Shurick**

Pragmatic Business Intelligence Engineer and Data Scientist; recent graduate of the Master of Information and Data Science (MIDS) from UC Berkeley; Extensive experience with SQL and Python for data processing and analysis. 11036 E Riverside Dr.
Bothell, WA 98011
(253)-222-2982
brandon.shurick@gmail.com
http://brandonshurick.com

#### **EXPERIENCE**

# Amazon, Seattle — Business Intelligence Engineer

OCTOBER 2016 - PRESENT

Data warehouse management, data modeling, production machine learning model creation and deployment, ad hoc data analysis.

### **TravelBird**, Amsterdam — Sr. BI Engineer / Data Scientist

JUNE 2015 - JUNE 2016

Responsible for AB testing analysis and development of customer-facing product recommendation engine, as well as development and maintenance of global business intelligence dashboards and data warehouse infrastructure.

## **Westwing Group GmbH,** Munich — *Sr. BI / DWH Developer*

JULY 2014 - MAY 2015

Led global business intelligence infrastructure improvements, including migration of data warehouse from MySQL to Vertica, and contributed to inferential analysis of customer and operational data.

### **T-Mobile USA**, Bellevue — Sr. Product Engineer, Analyst

JANUARY 2009 - JUNE 2014

Created internally-facing data product prototypes, analyzed mobile device data, designed mobile software product requirements, and led mobile product development via managed software development vendor.

#### **EDUCATION**

# **UC Berkeley,** Berkeley — Master of Information and Data Science

**JANUARY 2015 - AUGUST 2016** 

Data science coursework and projects spanning a wide range of concepts, including data visualization, descriptive and inferential statistics, machine learning at scale, experiments, and big data processing.

# **University of Washington,** Seattle — Bachelor of Arts in Business Administration (Finance, Information Systems)

SEPTEMBER 2004 - JUNE 2008

Business administration studies with additional coursework in Finance and Information Systems.

#### **SKILLS**

Python Sklearn & Scipy stack

SQL and data modeling

Data visualization and analysis

Big Data architectures

Web development

#### **AWARDS**

Hal R. Varian MIDS

Capstone Award Recognition
for top project out of UC
Berkeley MIDS Capstone
submissions, Summer 2016

Annual Dean's List University of Washington 2007-2008

#### **PROJECTS**

MIDS Capstone Project (http://goaltick.info)

Data Storage & Retrieval Streaming Twitter Storage (http://goo.gl/U3yZvq)

Field Experiment: Video or Text Math Education (https://bit.ly/2kM3wPj)